Translator
字 幕 入 力
ssnake
ssnake
ἐκκλησία
エクレシア
From now on, the Soul Church will
これより　魂召会による
Timing
字 幕 編 集
zwc1991
zwc1991
απάθεια
απάθεια
όρκα
όρκα
hold an inquisition on the former apatheia corps commander, Orca.
元アパトイア軍団長官　オルカへの審問会を開始する
φάλαινα
φάλαινα
Although we have to keep the sinners of Fallaina,
大砂海へ流罪に処した　ファレナの罪人たちが
who has been exiled to the great sea of sand, from being found by
スィデラシア連合王国および　その他の国々に発見されることは
the United Kingdom of Sidelasia and other countries.
避けなければならなかった
φάλαινα
φάλαινα
But Fallaina is in exile at the evil water.
だが　ファレナの流刑海域は魔の海域
It should be extremely difficult to approach and even discover them.
接近も発見も困難を極めるはず
φάλαινα
φάλαινα
The annihilation of Fallaina,
ファレナ殲滅は
was not an action that we have to take at this moment.
今すぐ行わねばならぬ作戦ではなかった
Who proposed and forced us to do that?
それを強行しようと提案したのは
It's you!
お前だ
Indeed, the exile judged 93 years ago
そもそも　93年前の流罪は
was a story for our citizens to take it as an example.
国内への見せしめの「ものがたり」であったのだ
By the story that the sinners revealed their emotions and conflicted ugly,
罪人たちが「感情」をあらわにし　醜く争う様は
our citizens can recognize the foolishness of having emotions again.
国民に感情の有ることの愚かさを再認識させる
And that's how you persuaded his Majesty as well as us.
お前はそう言って我々と陛下を説得したのだ
However, your strategy
しかし作戦は
failed.
失敗した
At his Majesty's command,
すでに皇帝陛下は断を下された
απάθεια
απάθεια
όρκα
όρκα
apatheia corps commander Orca, the chief executive of this action,
本作戦の最高責任者であるアパトイア軍団長官オルカ
σκύλος
σκύλος
αράχνη
αράχνη
Arakhne, the commander of skulax,
およびスキロス司令官アラフニ
as well as other hundreds of people are sentenced to death.
以下百余名を死刑に処す
Is that...
それが…
the best story you may tell?
ものがたり
What's wrong?
何がおかしい？
Excuse me.
失礼
I just... thought it was a little shabby.
少し…お粗末だと思ってしまったもので
What?
何？
Keep from responding to his provocation!
彼の挑発に乗ってはならぬ
Long long ago,
あるとき
The heaven cut a piece of its body,
からだ
and gave it to the world it has once rejected.
この世界に与え降らせたといいます
Thanks to that, the old bad civilization had faced its death and rebirth.
これにより　古き悪しき文明は一度死を迎えました
καθαρτήριο
καθαρτήριο
That is the tale of the rain of purgatory
それが　「カサルティリオの雨」という言い伝え
Then, what are we?
では　我々は何者なのですか？
νοῦς
ヌース
After the world had been cleaned up, we worshiped Nous, the body of heaven.
世界が洗い清められた後　神の体である「魂形」を崇め
We got its power.
その力を得て
νοῦς
ヌース
And we determined to deposit our minds, the roots of our faults, with Nous.
かつての過ちの根源である心を魂形に預ける決意をした
Then, we have two types of human beings in the world.
そして　この世界には2種類の人間が生まれた
νοῦς
ヌース
The evangelists of Nous, and those who can't be evangelists.
魂形の御使いに成れる者と成れぬ者
Evangelists are called Shirushi, and those who can't are Muin.
成れる者を「印」　成れぬ者を「無印」という
Well, now let's talk about something you may have already forgotten.
さて…ここからは皆さんお忘れのことかもしれません
There are a third type of human beings.
第3の人類が存在したことを
The third...?
第3…？
δαίμονας
デモナス
That's the Daímonas
…それは「悪霊」
νοῦς
ヌース
The ultimate warrior created by Nous with its power.
魂形の力によって創られた最強の戦士
δαίμονας
δαίμονας
Daímonas is just a rumor.
デモナスなど伝説にすぎぬ
That's how we forgot these, treating them as the bygones.
そうやって我々は過去の産物として忘却してきた
But now we can't pretend as they are not existing.
しかし　もう見て見ぬふりはできない
σκύλος
σκύλος
φάλαινα
φάλαινα
The boy in Fallaina who destroyed Skulax,
スキロスを破壊したファレナの少年
δαίμονας
デモナス
he is exactly the Daímonas!
彼こそが悪霊
Let me redifine it here:
私は改めて定義します
δαίμονας
δαίμονας
Daímonas is the threat that came back to our empire.
「デモナス」とは　帝国に再来した脅威
They have the power to overturn our country, which should be an ark.
方舟であるこの国を転覆させる力を持つ
They are the recognition of some terrible sins.
恐るべき罪の権化
After you have seen such an existence...
そのような存在を目にしながら…
αράχνη
αράχνη
Arakhne!
アラフニ
How did you treat him?
お前は彼をどう扱った？
According to the records, you despised and abused him.
記録によるとその者を侮り　罵倒し
And you even provoked him!
挑発したとなっているようだが？
I was...
…私は
I can't say you are innocent.
まったく罪がないとは言わせぬ
No, I can even say you are badly...
いや　むしろ罪の重さについては…
Shit!
くそッ！
No... no!
ち　ちがうっ！
Because Orca pulled his weapon...
オルカが先に武器を…
Weapon?
武器？
The records are full of blood...
記録が血だらけだ…
Who had assigned missions to such a guy,
このような感情の制御もできない者に
who can't even control his emotions?
任務を与えたのは誰でしょう
ἐκκλησία
あなた方
It's you!
魂召会だ
Even you have never been to the battle field,
たとえ戦場におらずとも
νοῦς
ヌース
don't forget it's your fault to have thee Nous sank.
魂形を沈めたその責任をお忘れなきように
Now let's turn to the new chapter of our story.
それではそろそろ物語の「新章」を紐解くとしましょうか
You say the new chapter?
「新章」だと？
It is quite possible that
そう遠くない未来に
καθαρτήριο
καθαρτήριο
a second rain of purgatory will fall in the near future.
「第2のカサルティリオの雨」が降る可能性がある
Don't change the topic!
話をすり替えるつもりか！
How dare you live without even a single sense of crisis!
…危機感のない人たちだ
This world can't be clean unless it is washed and cleaned again.
今一度洗い流さねば　この世界は清められない
And at that time we must protect this country,
そしてその刻に「方舟」となるこの国を
which will become an ark.
守らなければならない
δαίμονας
デモナス
Daímonas should be controlled by our country.
悪霊は　我が国が掌握する
Why do you want to control the Daímonas?
δαίμονας
φάλαινα
φάλαινα
We can just destroy it along with the Fallaina.
ファレナもろとも滅ぼしてしまえばいいではないか？
Who can?
誰が…
δαίμονας
誰がデモナスを始末するのです？
νοῦς
δαίμονας
Or you mean if the Daímonas sinks another Nous,
νοῦς
you will just execute those who involved?
その関係者を処刑して？
And make it as if nothing happened?
すべてをなかったことにして？
Shut up!
口を慎め！
Your brains are just like the ruins under the sea,
海に沈む遺跡のように！
badly corroded with rust!
錆び付いた頭で！
Take your story of devastation!
あなた達の破滅の物語を突き進むがいい！
What can you do in this situation?
…お前なら何ができるというのだ
δαίμονας
δαίμονας
I will capture the Daímonas for you.
デモナスを捕らえてみせます
Only I can make it.
私にならできます
δαίμονας
δαίμονας
Daímonas rewrited the theory of this world.
デモナスは世界の理を書き換える
The presence of it will lead our country to the absolute hegemon of the world!
その存在は我が国を世界の絶対覇者へと導く
Isn't it?
そうでしょう？
δαίμονας
δαίμονας
I did well until the discovery of Daímonas.
デモナスの発見まではよし
There is only one thing I have to regret.
悔やむべきはただひとつ
σκύλος
σκύλος
αράχνη
αράχνη
That is the arbitrariness of Arakhne the Skulax commander.
スキロス司令官アラフニの独断専行
What?
なっ！
All right. We leave him to you.
よかろう　部下の始末はお前に任せる
Wait... Wait a minute!
まっ…待ってくれ
όρκα
όρκα
You dare! Orca!
貴様っ！　オルカ！
Orca!!!
オルカーッ！
νοῦς
ヌース
Heaven blesses the servants of Nous!
魂形のしもべに天佑のあらんことを
Excuse me?
失礼
ατσάλι
ατσάλι
απάθεια
απάθεια
Dear Atsali, our current commander of apatheia corps
アツァリ　現アパトイア軍団長官殿
The finish of inquisition
審問を終えたからといって
doesn't mean your failure has been canceled out.
君の失策が帳消しになったわけではないのだぞ
I understand.
もちろんです
But there is no point in pulling your leg.
だがあなたの前でとりつくろっても仕方がない
Let me tell you straight away.
単刀直入に申し上げます
καρχαρίας
καρχαρίας
Give me the battleship Karcharías.
戦艦カルハリアスを私にいただきたい
σκύλος
σκύλος
But you have just lost Skulax.
スキロスを失ったばかりだというのにか？
If you agreed to give it to me, the church will accept.
長官が譲ると言ってくだされば　議会も言うことを聞くでしょう
What's up?
何か？
Do you remember the first time you talked with me?
君は私と初めて話したときのことを　覚えているかね？
I forgot.
忘れました
You don't need to give it to me immediately.
今すぐにとは申しますまい
You can have some days to think it over.
数日お考えいただいて結構です
I'm waiting for your good news.
よきお返事を待っていますよ
What were you talking about?
何の話をされていたんですか？
Something about the dream.
夢の話だ
You Shirushi have had a same dream?
「印」が皆同じ夢を…？
Yes.
そうです
In that dream, a girl entered our ears and sang a song.
少女が耳の中に入ってきて　歌を歌う夢です
What did... it imply?
それは…一体何の暗示でしょう
And after all, for us Muin who didn't have that dream,
そもそも夢を見ていない「無印」の私たちには
it is difficult to get over it.
今ひとつ事情が飲み込めなくて
Don't worry!
大丈夫です！
We understand it, I think.
たぶん　ボクらにはわかります！
♪　ラララ…
♪　ラララ…
♪　私たちを
♪　私たちを
♪　見つけておくれ
♪　見つけておくれ
The mud whale is advancing!
泥クジラが進んでいく…
Creatures are amazing.
いきものは不思議だ
♪　泥の船で櫂を漕ぎ
♪　泥の船で櫂を漕ぎ
Nobody has taught the star locusts,
ホシボシバッタは　誰に教わったわけでもないのに
♪　白砂の褥で眠る
♪　白砂の褥で眠る
Sleeping in the white sand
同じリズムで光を明滅させる
The migratory birds know where to go since they were born.
渡り鳥は　生まれたときから行く先を知っている
We are the same.
私たちも同じだ
♪　小さな旅人よ
♪　小さな旅人よ
We have already known
私たちは　すでに知っていた
how to move the mud whale.
泥クジラの動かし方を
♪　ただひとつになろうとしても
♪　ただひとつになろうとしても
They move the ship with such a game...
こんなお遊戯で動くとは
After all, that is this island.
全く　この島らしいね
How glory it is when all the residents gathered together.
住民全員集合とは壮観であるな
♪　無限のちらばりにしかなれない
♪　無限のちらばりにしかなれない
Roharito-sama.
ロハリト様
What?
うん？
Have you noticed?
お気づきで？
The percentage of young is too high.
若者の割合が多すぎます
Ya...
うむ…
What's wrong with you?
元気ないね？
The dream is too strange?
夢が不思議？
Or you are nervous about the guests?
それとも　お客さんのことが気になる？
I also worry about what I don't know.
俺だって知らないものはこわいよ
But the coming of guests,
でも　お客さんが来たことと
κόκαλο
κόκαλο
the understanding of Kókkalo after the dream,
夢を見てコカロの正体が分かったこと
don't you think they mean we are connecting with somebody else?
誰かが繋げてくれた気がするんだ
We are really departing again.
これが　本当の再出発なんだ
Yes.
…そうね
That's something only the Shirushi know.
「印」たちだけが知ってるなんて
As a Muin, I feel a little lonely.
「無印」としては　ちょっと寂しいですね
But now we can go wherever we want with the mud whale.
でも　これで泥クジラは好きなところに行ける
Wherever...
どこにだって…
Even where the empire's fang can't reach!
帝国の牙が届かぬところにも
Was there a plague in the island?
この島は疫病でも流行ったのか？
Or the adults died when the empire attacked you?
それとも　帝国からの襲撃で大人は死んでしまったのか？
As I told you before
以前話した通りです
it's because Shirushi is short-lived.
「印」が短命だから
As a result, we seems to have too many young people.
結果的に若者が大勢いるように見えるんです
The soldiers of empire can use the same power as those on the island.
帝国の兵士はこの島の者と同じ力を使う
But I have never heard of other short-lived races.
だが　かように短命な種族など　他に聞いたことがない
Who are you, the people of this island?
この島の民たちは何者なのだ？
I don't know.
分かりません
You hiding monkey! You just don't wanna tell me!
このオトボケザル！　余をたばかるつもりか！
I really don't know.
本当です
If I know it,
それが分かれば
I don't need to make these herbal medicine for prolonging life!
寿命を延ばすための薬草など　作りません！
Bring me to your room.
そなたの部屋に案内しろ
Eh?
えっ？
Be quick!
早く来い！
I will show you the world.
そなたに世界を見せてやる
This is the chart my ship used.
これが余の船が用いていた海図だ
Cha...rt?
かい…ず？
A map shows what the sea is like.
海がどうなっているか記した地図だ
I can't understand a single...
どういうことか　全く…
You guys are really ignorant monkeys...
そなたらは本当に無知な猿だな…
Listen.
いいか
Here is the United Kingdom of Sidelasia where our Duchy of Amonlogia belongs to.
ここが我らアモンロギアの属する　スィデラシア連合王国
My ship was like this... crossed the sea of sand to the west.
余の船はこう…西へ砂の海を渡っていったのだ
Then we were swallowed into a strange torrent here.
そして　ここで奇妙な海流に飲み込まれ
We were just about to wreck.
危うく難破しかけた
Some days after we crossed that,
ここを乗り越えて　数日後
we landed this island.
この島へ着いたのだ
So the mud whale is here!
泥クジラは　ここにあるんだ
Hey Suo! Return it!
こら　スオウ！　返すのだ！
So the island without rudder was taken by the torrent,
で　舵のないこの島は海流の動きに沿って
and you were wandering in the same area for sure.
同じ海域をさまよっていたのでしょうな
Exactly!
その通り！
It's a evil sea nobody has ever been.
これまで誰も近づけぬ魔の海域だったが
But I crossed that dangerous area,
余は危険な海域を越え
and found this island. What a great achievement!
この島を発見するという　偉業を成し遂げたのだ
That's it.
そうか…
We only know the ships of the empire
海流を自分の意思で越えられるのは
can cross the torrent with one's own will.
これまでは帝国の船だけだった
That's why the mud whale with its rudder deprived
だから舵を奪われていた泥クジラは
could go nowhere.
どこにも行けなかった
A bird in the cage...
籠の鳥…
This sea is a natural prison.
この海は自然の牢獄だったのね…
You were attacked by the biggest enemy of our country.
そなたらを襲撃したのは　我が国の最大の敵国
If you enter our bosom,
我が懐に入らば
we can definitely protect you, small birds in cage.
か弱き籠の鳥をかくまってやらんこともない
Roharito!
ロハリト
That country lies in the further west sea of sand.
「かの国」は　ここよりさらに西方の砂海にある
It's a strange country with no name.
名前を持たぬ奇妙な国よ
No name?
名前がない？
I don't know the reason.
理由は分からんが
But in that country, people don't have their real names.
「かの国」では　人民は本当の名を持たぬのだ…
This island is now heading for the Amonlogia in the east.
この島は現在　東のアモンロギアへ向かいつつある
Since you now have the rudder, you should be able to break through this torrent.
舵を得た今なら　この海流を突破できるであろう
Beyond that...
その先は…
A brand new world is waiting for you!
見たことのない世界が待っているぞ
What's the case? It's already so late.
用は何だ？　こんな夜更けに
I have something to tell you.
話があるの
I noticed it since the first sight.
初めて見た時から気づいておった
Your skin has different color than those on the island.
肌の色がこの島の者とは違う
You must... from that country.
そなたは…「かの国」の者だな…
What's your words? Tell me.
用はなんだ　申してみよ…
Stop looking up the people on the island.
この島の人たちのことを調べるのをやめて…
What do you mean?
…どういうことだ
Stop talking with them until we reach your country.
あなたの国へ着くまで　人々の話は中断しなさい…
No, it's impossible.
いや　それはできぬ
How can we accept a short-lived clans of unknown reason?
原因不明の短命な一族を　邦に受け入れられると思うか？
They may have some plague.
伝染する病かもしれんのだぞ
That's not the case.
それは違うわ
So you know the reason.
原因を知っているのだな
Hmm?
ん？
Lykos?
…リコス…？
If you don't tell me what they are clearly,
民の正体がはっきりせぬなら
I can't promise you to take their side.
味方をするという保証はできぬ
The cause is the mud whale.
原因は泥クジラよ
Mud whale...
泥クジラ…
You mean this ship?
この船のことか？
The reason why this ship as well as the ships of empire can float on the sea
この船や帝国の船を海に浮かべているのは
νοῦς
ヌース
is because a creature named Nous.
魂形という生き物
The Nous in my country eat the emotions of people.
νοῦς
sentikinesis
サイミア
and give them the power of thymia in return.
かわりに「情念動」という能力を授ける
They are called the Shirushi.
それが　「印」と呼ばれる人々
νοῦς
νοῦς
φάλαινα
φάλαινα
But only the Nous on the island, Fallaina, has a different role.
でも　この島のヌース　「ファレナ」だけは役割が違うの
Different role? What's it?
違う…？　どういうことだ？
Lykos...
リコス…
φάλαινα
φάλαινα
The food of Fallaina, and the source of Shirushi's thymia,
ファレナが食べ　「印」のサイミアの元になり
which makes the island floating on the sea,
この島を浮かせているのは…
is the lives of Shirushi living on the mud whale!
泥クジラで生きる…
Ah...
あっ…
Chakuro!
チャクロ！
Wait, Chakuro!
待って　チャクロ！
It's not easy.
楽ではないな…
Hearing the bitter truth,
辛い話を聞かされることと
and living without knowing the bitter truth,
辛い話を知らされずにいること
no matter which you choose...
どちらを選んでも…
I knew it some how.
何となく分かっていた
But I pretended as I didn't know.
でも　見ないようにしてた
I didn't want to know it.
知りたくなかった
So I avoided it.
だから避けていたんだ…
Always...
ずっと…
Lykos.
リコス
We have made up our minds since you come here.
あなたがここに来た時から　覚悟はしていました
But...
…でも
It's the only thing we want to keep secret.
このことだけは明らかにしたくなかった…
So the presbytery knows it...
長老会はずっと知っていたんですね
Sorry, Suo, and everybody...
ごめんなさいね　スオウ　みんな…
No.
いいえ
We will continue to support the Shirushi.
これからも「印」を支えていくことに
There is no difference.
変わりはありません
That's impossible.
ふん！　そうはいかん
After you get into the world outside, you will definitely notice it someday.
外の世界に出れば　いつかは気づくことだ
Or you just stay in the cage named Fallaina?
それとも　このままファレナの檻にとどまるか…
Hey, what's up?
おい　何なんだよ
Start it now!
早く始めろよ
Why these guys want to hole an assembly?
何だってあいつらがこんな集会なんか
Aren't the twins the bad eggs of the internal moles?
あの双子　体内モグラの不良だろ
This is made by the wings of birds shot with thymia!
これはサイミアで落とした鳥の翼でできている！
And this is a flag made for making an oath!
そして　誓いを立てるために造った旗だ
Under this flag, we will
この旗のもと　俺たちは
form a new leader group, the rudder of purple wing!
泥クジラの新しい先導者集団　「紫翼の舵」を結成し！
And this is our rally!
決起集会を行う！
We know we are not trusted by you guys!
俺たちがお前らに信用されてねえことは分かってる！
So we don't expect everybody's agree here!
だから今ここにいる全員に賛同してもらおうって気はねえ
But since you were born,
ただ　お前らが生まれた時から
you did never doubt the system of this dolls world!
人形みてえに世界の在り方に疑いを持ってねえことに
This is a puzzle for us!
俺たちはずっとモヤモヤしてた
We had been making troubles on the mud whale.
俺たちが今まで　泥クジラのはじっこで尖ってたのも
Because we couldn't blow the cobweb away!
そのモヤモヤが昔っから晴れなかったからだ
Do you guys really believe
お前らの中に　この島の進む方向が
the island is on a trip to the freedom?
本当に自由への旅だと思ってる奴はいるのか？
It is said that
泥クジラは
the mud whale is heading to the country of the guys landed recently.
こないだ船に乗り込んできた奴らの国に向かっているらしい
Who decided that?
それは誰が決めた！
It's not decided by you, right?
お前らじゃないよな！
Of course not.
そりゃそうだろ
The decisions of this island are made by the presbytery of Muin.
この島のことは無印の長老会が決めるんだから
Yes!
そうだ
Since long long before we were born!
俺たちが生まれる前からそうだった！
And you think it's right.
そして　お前らはそれが正しいと思ってる
Isn't it right?
それの何がいけないの
Then we'll ask you another question.
質問を変えてやる
During the recent war, how many Shirushi died?
この間の戦闘で　「印」は何人死んだと思う
I... I don't want to recall that.
…お　思い出したくないよ
Why you need to ask this now?
なんで今　そんなこと聞く必要があるんだよ
There are so many died that you don't want to recall!
思い出したくないほど死んだんだろ！
Hakuji from the presbytery is the only Muin died in the attack from Skulax.
スキロスの攻撃で死んだ「無印」は　長老会のハクジだけ
Only one!
たった一人だ！
Remember the operation the presbytery raised that time!
あの時　長老会が考えた作戦を思い出してみろ！
They made trained Shirushi fight in the island.
島では訓練した印を戦わせ
And hide the Muin in the safe places of the mud whale.
無印は泥クジラの安全な場所に隠れていた
We had to do that!
仕方ないだろ
The Muin without thymia is no help for the fights.
サイミアのない無印が戦ったって　どうにもならない
Yes.
そうよ
It's even more difficult to fight while protecting the Muin.
無印を守りながら戦うなんて　そっちのほうが無茶だろ
Yes, they would be the drags on us!
だよな　足手まといっていうか
Yes!
そうだ
The Muin is exactly the drags on us!
本来無印は「足手まとい」なんだ
Don't you think it's cowardly?
卑怯だと思わねえのか
They are unable to use thymia, they can't do anything themselves.
サイミアも使えず　自分たちは何もできない
They are pieces of shit who just have long lives!
寿命だけが長い役立たず
Such guys set the operations for their own benefits,
そんな奴らが　自分に都合のいい作戦を立て
and disposed of us Shirushi!
俺たち印を使い捨て
How can we abandon that!
見殺しにしていいわけがないだろ！
Didn't you ever doubt it?
今まで全く疑問に思わなかったのか？
You should know it!
分かっただろ！
The system of the mud whale itself is a rotten cheat!
泥クジラの仕組み自体が　腐ったまやかしなんだよ！
We will release us Shirushi from the dominance of Muin!
俺たちは「印」を　「無印」の支配から解放する！
We Shirushi decide where we shall go!
どこへ進むかは「印」が決める！
The ship should be ruled by us Shirushi,
この船は俺たち印が！
by the rudder of purple wing!
「紫翼の舵」が実権を握るんだ！
Thymia is the power driving the mud whale.
サイミアは泥クジラを動かす力だ
The strength of thymia decides where the mud whale go!
サイミアの強さが　泥クジラの行く先を決める！
Power is everything!
力が全てになるんだ！
We rule the mud whale?
俺たちが泥クジラを？
We go against the presbytery?
長老会に逆らうっていうの？
Why not!
それのどこが悪い
Stop it! It is prohibited to use thymia in violence!
やめろ！サイミアを使った暴力は禁止だぞ！
What? Isn't is a rule set by the Muin?
はっ！それも無印が決めたルールじゃねえか
Oni!
オウニ！
Stop the meaningless violence.
無意味な暴力をふるおうとするな
Even you become a dog of Muin?
お前まで無印の犬になっちまったのかよ
I'm on nobody's side.
俺は誰の側にもつかない
But you were the internal moles.
ただ　お前らは体内モグラだった
I don't like you to be this crappy.
安っぽい姿は見たくない
Crappy?
安っぽいだと？
Hey what's up?
オイオイ　どうした
You run out of power? Together with your motivation.
力なくしちまったのかよ　やる気と一緒に
Say it Oni, you take our side.
言えよオウニ　俺たち側につくって
You are the most bloody devil in the island!
お前はこの島で
You are the strongest monster killed a number of enemies.
敵を何人も殺した　最強の魔物じゃねえか
Listen, you guys!
てめえらもよく聞け！
We are strong!
俺たちは強い！
We are different from Muin!
「無印」とは違う！
We have thymia!
俺たちにはサイミアがある！
乾いた海の跡　望んで
乾いた海の跡　望んで
With this power,
この力があれば
nobody will insult us, trample us again!
二度とバカにされ　踏みにじられることはねえ！
Is that true?
そうなのか…
まだ見ぬ対岸を描く
まだ見ぬ対岸を描く
I will draw the other side I have never seen
いや　無理だ
Hey, Oni.
なあ　オウニ
Let's show you the power of us.
俺たちの力を見せつけてやろうぜ
囚われの心のままなら
囚われの心のままなら
We will live strongly and freely.
強く　自由に生きるんだ…
κόκαλο
κόκαλο
The rudder named Kókkalo.
コカロという舵
こんな傷みも知らずにいた
こんな傷みも知らずにいた
And the freedom available from the rudder.
舵という自由
Though we have found more possibilities,
新たな可能性を見つけたというのに
the mud whale lost its destination
泥クジラは行き先を見失って
美しい詞を告げたひと
美しい詞を告げたひと
and started to wander.
さまよい始めていた
The yoke of the truth of our short-lives,
短命の真相というクビキが
was pressing me...
私を重く縛っていた…
夜明けも待たずに
夜明けも待たずに
果てのその先を泳ぐ
果てのその先を泳ぐ
虫の唄
虫の唄
眠らず君と聞いた記憶
眠らず君と聞いた記憶
手を　ただ結んで
手を　ただ結んで
半色でも　遠い国でも
半色でも　遠い国でも
短い一章に生まれた夢を
短い一章に生まれた夢を
抱きしめに行こう
抱きしめに行こう